http://www.eia.doe.gov/about/privacy_security_policy.php

About EIA
Privacy Statement and Security Policy
Privacy statement
This website (http://www.eia.gov/) is provided as a
public energy information service of the U.S. Energy Information Administration.
EIA.gov utilizes web measurement software tools in order to improve the efficiency of our website and to provide a better user experience for our customers.
If you visit this site to read or download information, you should know that EIA collects and stores a standard set of Internet-related information, such as an Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time, the type of browser and operating system used, the page(s) visited, and if you linked to the EIA website from another website, the address of that website.
The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) classifies this as a Tier 2 usage since we utilize multi-session web measurement technologies that do not collect any personally identifiable information (PII).
These technologies anonymously track how visitors interact with EIA.gov, including where they came from, what they did on the site, and whether they completed any pre-determined tasks while on the site.
We use Google Analytics and IBM's NetInsight web measurement technologies.
This information is used to optimize our website; improve our user interface and ensure our content meets the needs of our customers. No personally identifiable information is collected, so the anonymity of the
user is protected.
The measurement data that is collected is only retained for as long as is needed for proper analysis and optimization of the website and is accessible only to employees whose position necessitates it.
Since disabling this web measurement technology requires you to modify your individual browser settings, it is enabled by default.
If you wish to opt-out from these web measurement technologies, you can find instructions for changing your browser settings at http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml.
Google also provides a browser plug-in that will allow you to opt-out of all Google Analytics measurements, which you can find at http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Please note that opting-out in no way effects your access to content or how you see the site.
If you send us personal information and/or subscribe to EIA's e-mail
notification system (e-lists)
If you choose to provide us with personal information such as submitting information through the website on our Feedback page (www.eia.gov/about/feedback), e-mail subscription lists, or in an e-mail to EIA's Information Center, or to any EIA email (@eia.gov) we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. EIA does not give, sell, or transfer personal information to third parties, unless required by law, such as the Freedom of Information Act.
If you participate in
EIA's social media activities
EIA is committed to
expanding access to its information and engaging its customers and
stakeholders. One of the
key ways we seek to accomplish this is through
the use of third-party
social media websites and applications. We do not
collect or request
personally identifiable information through these outlets,
but may
occasionally come into contact with unsolicited PII due to
circumstances beyond our control. As a result, we reserve the right to
moderate
or remove comments that offer personally identifiable
information such as
address, phone number or social security number in a
public manner. No PII will
be retained in our system or shared with
outside parties.
Security, intrusion, and detection
For site security purposes, and
to ensure this
service remains available to all users, this Government computer
system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify
unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise
cause
damage.
Operations security program
The U.S. Energy Information Administration
maintains a program (Operations Security [OPSEC]) that is designed to
protect
information collected in EIA's surveys. This Program takes the
form of various
elements such as: staff security training, pre-hire
certification, and integrity
of EIA data systems, fair practice data
disclosure policies, and the physical
security of all sensitive
unclassified EIA data. If you have any questions
concerning this
program, please contact Keith Rapoza, phone (202) 586-2626.
Links to other sites
Our website has links to many other websites including government (Federal, State, local, and international) agencies, universities, trade associations, energy companies, and selected other websites. All links that navigate you away from www.eia.gov are denoted by the
icon.
If you navigate to another site, you will be subject to the privacy policy of that site.
Security policy
This website is part of a federal computer system used to accomplish federal functions. The U.S. Energy Information Administration continuously monitors this website for security purposes to ensure it remains available to all users and to protect information in the system. By accessing this website, you are expressly consenting to these monitoring activities.
Unauthorized attempts to defeat or circumvent security features, to use the system for other than intended purposes, to deny service to authorized users, to access, obtain, alter, damage, or destroy information, or otherwise to interfere with the system or its operation is prohibited. Evidence of such acts may be disclosed to law enforcement authorities and result in criminal prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996 (Pub. L. 104-294), (18 U.S.C. 1030), or other applicable criminal laws.
Automated retrieval program (robot) activity
EIA is committed to providing data promptly and according to established schedules.
Therefore any automated retrieval program (commonly referred to as a "robot" or "bot") that excessively accesses information from EIA's website is prohibited. Excessive robot activity on EIA's website can cause delays and interfere with other customers' timely access to information.
EIA will block robots that are accessing the
website in any way that EIA
considers excessive or malicious,
including robots that attempt to access or
download survey information
multiple times per second with resulting degradation
of service to
others. EIA also reserves the right to block robots that do not
contain contact information that can be used to contact the owner.
Blocking may
occur in real time.
NOTE: Robots using a specific IP
address instead of an official EIA URL (examples: www.eia.gov or
ir.eia.gov) are at risk for not receiving data promptly at prescribed
times.
Trouble accessing the EIA website?
EIA uses industry standard "blackhole" lists, maintained by public and private institutions in the larger Internet community, to defensively block access to our web servers.
Please understand that EIA does not maintain these lists and we cannot remove you from them.
We suggest you alert your network security officer (for businesses and organizations) or your internet service provider (for individuals).
EIA Documentary (video)
Statement of Commitment to Scientific Integrity by Principal Statistical Agencies
